Robert Cawood

10 Whitley Avenue, Barnton, Northwich, Cheshire. CW8 4LW Mobile: 07508842916 Email: rfcawood@gmail.com

PROFILE

A highly professional ITIL qualified IT Support & Delivery Manager with over 20 years IT industry experience gained in both Public and Private sectors with particular knowledge of the Education sector and the Insurance industry. Possessing excellent customer service, communication (both oral and written) and client facing skills with good business acumen gained in various environments.

KEY SKILLS / COMPETENCIES

- Staff/People Management: Line management, performance management, 1-2-1 reviews, coaching and mentoring.
- Infrastructure Management: Provision of support and management of an infrastructure from core elements to various end user devices.
- Technical Knowledge: Virtualisation, Microsoft Server & desktop environments, Active Directory, Group Policy, O365, Windows 7 and Microsoft Office desktop applications
- Change Management: Extensive experience of successfully introducing and implementing change in a demanding environment.
- Third Party Management: Negotiated supply and service contracts with third parties, establishing and monitoring SLAs and performance indicators.
- Project Management: Successfully delivered infrastructure and desktop migration projects in a demanding environment.
- Stakeholder management: Clear delivery focused communication at all levels of the organisation.

KEY EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

IT & Data Manager

September 2014 onwards

Hazel Grove High School

- Management of a team covering the areas of IT Support, data administration & VLE/Website administration,
- Mentoring, training & coaching of team members including Apprentices.
- Management and hands-on administration of a virtualised Microsoft based server infrastructure including Active Directory, Group Policies and Office 365. Virtualisation of servers using VMWare.
- Ensuring incidents and changes are dealt with within agreed timescales.
- Manage 3rd party supplier contracts including service provision.
- Inventory management of both hardware and software, ensuring the team keep all details up to date.
- Responsibility for IT Acceptable Use. Data Protection and Disaster Recovery policies.
- Provide statistical data analysis reports to senior staff and board members.
- Department budget management of up to £100,000 ensuring best value and purchasing in line with institution targets.

Contractor/Consultant

May 2013 August 2014

Providing IT and Data advice and support to public sector clients, including Network Infrastructure audit, Database design, MIS support and advice, Key performance indicator analysis, Server and desktop support.

Strategic IT & Data Manager

Sept 2011 - Apr 2013

Salford City Council / Oakwood Academy

- IT Service management, 3rd party / outsourced provider management including monthly reviews and analysis of performance against agreed service levels.
- Incident, change & problem management to ensure the efficient delivery of IT services.
- Strategic IT vision planning.
- Project management analysis of need, budget planning, stakeholder dialogue and delivery.
- Contract negotiation & management.
- IT Budget responsibility of up to £100k and collectively with Leadership for over £3m.
- Technical and operational documentation.
- Asset management.
- Responsibility for the management information system (MIS) ensuring promotion and use of modules, accuracy
 of data and reporting.
- Compile and present a termly KPI report to senior management providing an overview of effectiveness of the organisation.
- Organisation data analysis & reporting.
- Team management including 1-2-1 meetings/reviews and performance management appraisals

Senior management responsibility and decision making.

CV – R. Cawood Page 1 of 2

ICT Infrastructure Manager

Salford City Council / Oakwood High School

- Administration and support of a Microsoft based infrastructure including Active Directory, Group Policies, Exchange, HP switches and Mitel telephony.
- Support of client end devices including Microsoft and Apple desktops and Audio/Visual equipment.
- Third party contract/supplier negotiation
- IT Budget responsibility of up to £100k and collectively with Leadership for over £3m.
- Strategic IT vision planning.
- Technical and operational documentation.
- Asset management.
- Line management, coaching and mentoring of in-house and supply/contract IT technicians.
- Senior management responsibility and decision making.

Technical Support Team Leader

Apr 2000 - Dec 2001

Jan 2003 - Aug 2011

Memorex Telex (2000 – 2001)

- Team Leader for a technical support team of 10-15 2nd & 3rd line engineers providing a fully managed contracted support service.
- Allocating and monitoring of support calls ensuring contractual 4 hour fix SLA and 95% KPI.
- Production of weekly statistics including KPI reporting to IT management team
- Packaging software using MS SMS Installer and distributing throughout the company on up to 2000 Windows NT4 workstations.
- Technical resource for Projects from initiation, support documentation, implementation and hand-over.
- Identifying & solving trend incidents as a member of the Problem Management team.
- Identified as specialist knowledge & support for MS Office.

KEY CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS

- Improved IT support service and overall reputation of IT Support services within the organisation.
- Project managed a new virtualised server infrastructure ensuring system availability within restricted timeframe ready for important date/deadline.
- Joint project managed the successful infrastructure upgrade/migration change to a managed service infrastructure. This included end to end project management from solution design and initiation, budget management, resource planning and stakeholder management through to delivery.
- Appointed technical representative within a team to outsource IT Service Provision for the whole education estate
 of a Local Authority. The project included defining an output specification for the definition of services, developing
 KPI, SLA and performance measurements, evaluation of bidder proposals and decision making on contract
 reward.

FULL EMPLOYMENT SUMMARY

IT & Data Manager, <u>Hazel Grove High School</u> (2014 – present)

IT/Data Consultant & Contractor, (2013-2014)

IT Infrastructure Manager / Strategic IT & Data Manager, Salford City Council / Oakwood Academy (2003 – 2013)

Software Package Deployment Contractor, Unilever (2002 – 2002)

SMS Scripting Contractor, RAF Sealand (2002 – 2002)

Technical Support Team Leader, Memorex Telex (TUPE from Independent Insurance) (2000 - 2001)

Senior Field Support Engineer, Independent Insurance (1999 – 2000)

Project Managers Office Administrator, Barclays PLC (1999)

Regional Branch Support Analyst, Aon (1993 – 1998)

Construction/Commercial Insurance Broker, Aon (1989 - 1993)

Commercial Insurance Broker Alexander Stenhouse UK Ltd (1987 – 1989)

QUALIFICATIONS & TRAINING

Academic Qualifications

BTEC National Diploma - Business & Finance GCSEs incl. English, Mathematics and Physics

Technical Qualifications

Microsoft Certified Professional ITIL Foundation in Service Management

CV – R. Cawood Page 2 of 2